Guide to the Budget Office, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Budget Office, Yale University, records
1927-1985
RU 718
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
129
(126 boxes)
The records consist of reports, statements, and working files of the Yale Budget Office.
Yale University. Office of Finance and Administration
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 5-C (YRG 5-C), Budget records of Yale University.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of reports, statements, and working files of the Yale Budget Office.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Finance; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University. Office of Finance and Administration
- Records, 1953-1980; Accession 1979-A-022
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2016.
  - Yale Health Plan (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Records, 1966-1980; Accession 1981-A-049
  - 1966/1967-1968/1969 Transfers (Box 2)
  - 1966/1967-1968/1969 Transfers (cont'd) (Box 2A)
  - 1971-1976 Operations budgets; Vassar-Yale Report; Reading file B.O. 1969 Jul - 1978 Jul (Box 3)
  - 1973/1974-1976/1977 budget worksheets and files; 1973 3rd balance; 1976 2nd balance (Box 4)
  - 1974/1975 and 1975/1976 transfers; 1975 Jun operations (Box 6)
  - 1974/1975 and 1975/1976 transfers; 1975 Jun operations (cont'd) (Box 6A)
  - 1975/1976 budgets 20-31; investment reports and special studies (Box 7)
  - 1975/1976 budgets 20-31; investment reports and special studies (cont'd) (Box 7A)
  - 1975/1976 budgets 31-49 (Box 8)
  - 1975/1976 budgets 31-49 (cont'd) (Box 8A)
  - 1975/1976 budgets 50-60 and type codes (Box 9)
  - 1975/1976 budgets 50-60 and type codes (cont'd) (Box 9A)
  - 1975 3rd balance; 1976 2nd balance (Box 9B)
  - 1976/1977 budget (Box 10)
  - 1976/1977 budget (cont'd) (Box 10A)
  - 1976/1977 budget (cont'd) (Box 10B)
  - 1976/1977 budget (cont'd) (Box 11)
  - 1976/1977 budget (cont'd) (Box 11A)
  - 1976/1977 special studies (Box 12)
  - 1976/1977 special studies (cont'd) (Box 12A)
  - 1977/1978 budgets 20 to 31 (Box 13)
  - 1977/1978 budgets 20 to 31 (cont'd) (Box 13A)
  - 1977/1978 budgets 32 to 69 (Box 14)
  - 1977/1978 budgets 32 to 69 (cont'd) (Box 14A)
  - 1977/1978 budgets 32 to 69 (cont'd) (Box 14B)
  - 1977, 1978 Jun final and 1978 Jun 3rd balance, remaining balances of restricted funds (Box 15)
  - 1978 Jun remaining balances of restricted funds; 1979 Jun 3rd balance (Box 19)
- Records, 1969-1979; Accession 1982-A-049
  Restricted until January 1, 2030.
- Records, 1969-1979; Accession 1982-A-050
  The materials are open for research.
  - 1977-1978
  - 1976-1977
  - 1975-1976
  - 1974-1975
  - 1973-1974
  - 1972-1973
  - 1971-1972
    - Yale Health Plan, 1971 March (Box 3)
    - 1971-1972 Budget and 1972-1973 Outlook (3), 1971 November (Box 3)
    - 1971-1972 Estimate and 1972-1973 Budget, 1972 January (Box 3)
    - Yale University Comparison of Actual and Budgeted Income and Expenses 1971-1972, 1972 October (Box 3)
  - 1970-1971
    - Yale Health Plan, 1971 March (Box 3)
  - 1969-1970
  - 1968-1969
  - 1967-1968
  - 1966-1967
  - 1965-1966
  - 1964-1965
  - 1963-1964
  - 1962-1963
  - 1961-1962
  - 1954-1955
- Records, 1954-1982; Accession 1982-A-051
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2018.
  - "University Planning for Private Prestige Schools" Janet Louise Mangold, undated (Box 7, Folder 279)
  - Yale Health Plan HMO Legislation, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 299)
  - "Achieving Financial Equilibrium at Yale: A Report on the Budget Draft" (2 copies) (with comments and letters of response), 1977 November 15 (Box 7, Folder 324)
  - 1971/72 Budget and 1972/73 Projection R. N. Cooper, 1972 October (Box 8, Folder 330)
  - 1972/73 Budget and 1973/74 Projection R.N. Cooper, 1973 October (Box 8, Folder 332)
  - 1973/74 and 1974/75 Schedules, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 333)
  - 1974/75 Operating Budget R.N. Cooper, 1974 April (Box 8, Folder 334)
  - 1974/75 Proposed Budget, 1974 April 9 (Box 8, Folder 335)
  - 1974/75 Budget R. Cooper and B.O. Report, 1974 April 11 (Box 8, Folder 336)
  - 1973/74 Results 1974/75 Proposed R.N. Cooper, 1974 December (Box 8, Folder 337)
  - "Study of the Economics of Higher Educationat Yale University" (report), undated (Box 8, Folder 345)
  - Yale Health Plan Special Reports, 1973-1977 (Box 8, Folder 356)
  - "Effects of Inflation on College and University Finances'' T. Rowe Price, 1976 February 21 (Box 8, Folder 362)
- Records, 1952-1981; Accession 1982-A-052
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2017.
  - 1970-1971 Financial Plan Proposal to President Brewster (working notes), 1969 October (Box 2)
  - 1970-1971 Budget Progress Report, 1970 June (Box 2)
  - 1971-1972 Budget Planning Problems, 1970 September (Box 2)
  - 1971-1972 Interim Budget Report and Five Year Outlook, 1971 January (Box 2)
  - 1971-1972 Budget and 1972-1973 Outlook, 1971 November (Box 2)
  - 1971-1972 Comparison of Actual and Budgeted Income and Expenses, 1972 October (Box 2)
  - 1972-1973 Approved Budget by Unit School BT-1, 1972 October (Box 2)
  - 1973-1974 Budget Plan, Work Done to Date, 1972 November (Box 2)
  - 1973-1974 Approved Budget, By Unit, By School BT-1, 1973 October (Box 2)
  - 1974-1975 Preliminary Budget Information, 1973 September (Box 2)
  - Yale Finance and Administrative Meetings, 19 79 (Box 2)
  - Yale Financial Statements Supplement for the fiscal year ending 1980 Jun, 1980 June (Box 3)
  - Draft of Operating Income and Expense 1972-1973 to 1976-1977 Volume I, 1972-1977 (Box 3)
- Financial statements (microfiche), 1973-1981; Accession 1982-A-056
  Restricted to Office of Origin only
- Records, 1945-1982; Accession 1983-A-080
  - Yale Computer Center: pricing, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Yale Computer Center, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Yale Educational Corporation, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Yale University notices, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Yale University press releases, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Records, 1979-1982; Accession 1984-A-049
- Working papers, 1967-1980; Accession 1984-A-050
- Records, 1968-1984; Accession 1985-A-041
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2020.
- Records, 1982-1983; Accession 1985-A-042
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2019.
  - Xerox Copies of Material Sent to ADS, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 294)
- Records, 1940-1983; Accession 1985-A-043
- Records, 1967-1985; Accession 1985-A-044
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2021.
  - Divinity School, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Drama School, 1969-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Medical School, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Yale College, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Yale Dramatic Association, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 106 - 107)
- Budget Records, 1973-1985; Accession 1989-A-033
  - Economic indicator, 1979 January-1977 December (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Economic indicators, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Economic indicators, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Budget Records, 1927-Circa 1983; Accession 2001-A-106